

Miroslav Maksimović

E-mail: maksimovic991@gmail.com Website: http://elmaxi.github.io/resume

Phone : (381) 61 6128262 Address: Dragiše Brašovana 15 11070 Novi Beograd

Serbia

Summary

I'm a Web Developer based in Belgrade, Serbia, specialized in both back-end and front-end development. Possess considerable knowledge of the development of websites and web applications using PHP and MySQL. As a development environment I use LAMP and Vagrant which provides easy to configure, reproducible, and portable work environments.

Experience building WordPress driven websites.

A good knowledge of Laravel PHP Framework.

Quick learner who enjoys learning new skills and rapidly adapts to new technologies.

I'm currently working as a PHP Web Developer at Diwanee.

Work experience

Diwanee Jan 2015 — Present

PHP Web Developer

DSTV Multimedia Feb 2014 — May 2014

Web Developer

Responsibilities:

- Design, develop and improve company's websites.
- Develop new sites using Wordpress.
- · Maintain existing sites.
- Collaborate closely with the marketing team members to maintain, design and form content.
- Management of the company's hosting account.

Soko Group, Belgrade

October 2013 — Feb 2014

Web Developer

Responsibilities:

- Develop new as well as edit existing websites and write semantic markup.
- Develop new sites using Wordpress.
- Meeting with clients to identify their needs, discuss requirements and/or project progress.
- Coordinate with clients and provide support.
- Protects websites by taking security precautions.
- Management of the company's hosting account.

Statistical Office of the Republic of Serbia, Belgrade

July 2013 — August 2013

Miroslav Maksimović 1

Student Internship

The internship was in the form of a lectures. Employees from different departments were tasked to explain the practical application of database and application development. The internship was done as a requirement for graduation thesis.

Technical Skills

Programming languages: PHP, JavaScript

Libraries: jQuery

Frameworks: Laravel

Markup languages: HTML/HTML5, XML

Stylesheet languages: CSS/CSS3

DBMS: MySQL

NoSQL: MongoDB

CMS: WordPress

Version Control: Git

Tools: Composer, Bower, Jekyll

Development Environment: LAMP, Vagrant

Education

Business Informatics and e-business

October 2010 — November 2013

Belgrade Business School - Bachelor of Applied Science

During the studies, which lasted three years, I have acquired a basic knowledge of programming(OOP), databases, computer networks, information systems design, internet marketing, e-business, web development and design. The school is a part of Microsoft DreamSpark, which is a Microsoft program to provide students with software design and development tools at no charge, so we used Visual Studio, MS SQL Server, and other development tools for free. As a programming language we used C#, and ASP.NET framework for web development. One of the most important subjects in the studies were a Databases, where each team worked on the project as a requirement for passing the exam. My team and I worked on "Designing a database for preschool" project. As a requirement for thesis, I've done an intership in Statistical Office of the Republic of Serbia. Diploma thesis "The Concept of the Blog and the Blogosphere in Serbia" I passed with the highest grade.

Mechanical technician for computer engineering

September 2006 — Jun 2010

Aviation Academy - IV degree

Aviation Academy is the unique school in the region with eighty - eight- year – long tradition of training aviation personnel both in the field of civil and military aviation, certified by the European Aviation Safety Agency (EASA) and The Civil Aviation Directorate of the Republic of Serbia. Learning objectives for a period of four years for Mechanical technician for computer engineering is to train students for correct, accurate, creative and independent work in the form of various calculations, modeling parts, creating engineering drawings on computers, as well as the acquisition of other skills and knowledge in the broad field of mechanical engineering and metalworking.

Miroslav Maksimović 2

Courses and Conferences

Conferences

- Google Code Day Belgrade Fair 27. april 2014.
 - The aim of the conference was to exchange experiences with the review of the modern trends in programming through examples of best practices.
- PHP T-Day Belgrade Fair 22. november 2014.
 - This conference was aimed to inform participants about modern testing methods, trends, and best practices.

Interests

In my free time I enjoy spending time with my family and friends, traveling, working out, watching movies and sports, playing video games, and keeping up with information and technology changes and constantly learning new things.

Languages

- English professional working proficiency
- · Serbian native

Driving Licence

B category

Miroslav Maksimović 3